-[knocking]
-What?
They, um…
-They're ready for you out front.
-But if you need a moment, um…
-No.
No, let's just go. Come on.
I know it can be hard
being a woman in comedy
or even just, like,
a woman in general, so…
Why are you being weird?
-Um, I'm just…
-Take that off.
[intriguing music plays]
Can you get someone
to wipe that stuff off the mirror?
-I don't know what that was.
-Yeah, of course. Okay.
Um, all right.
Do you want a hug?
-I'm okay.
-You sure?
-Yeah.
-Okay. All right. I love you.
-[man] Ladies and gentlemen…
-What?
-[man] …non-binary individuals…
-Good luck.
-[man] … esteemed members of the LGBTQ…
-Thanks.
[man] …please welcome Mary Beth Barone!
[cheering and applause]
[upbeat music plays]
-I'm Mary Beth.
-[cheering]
Welcome to Galaxy Brain.
[cheering]
This is the first Netflix special ever
to be done completely in vocal fry.
[cheering]
They're letting me do it
in my native dialect.
[laughter]
And they found
such beautiful crisis actors.
-You'll get your checks on the way out.
-[whooping]
-What's your name?
-Victoria.
Victoria. And what's the main thing
you do for work?
[Victoria] Um, I'm a medical assistant
at an abortion clinic.
Medical assistant at an abortion clinic?
[cheering and applause]
And what's your body count?
[laughter]
Actually, why don't we
all just say our body counts?
I'm gonna count to three
and we'll just say 'em. I'll do it too.
I hope no one's here on a first date.
[laughter]
Or maybe that's good.
So I'm gonna count to three
and we're all just gonna say it.
Ready? One, two, three.
[indistinct shouting]
Okay, some of you didn't say.
[laughter]
I was like, "I'm gonna count,
we're all gonna say our body counts,"
then some of you said nothing.
How do you think that makes Victoria feel?
[laughter]
It's not a way to build community.
And I won't forget it.
I met with Netflix and they said that
I have three minutes to win people over.
The most people
that are gonna click away from the special
will do so in the first three minutes.
Imagine if that happened in real life
and most of you were gone already.
[laughter]
"I'm not really fucking with this.
Let's go watch Emily in Paris."
[laughter]
They said I had to be likable, accessible,
and non-controversial for three minutes.
[laughter]
It's, like, impossible.
Everyone's so sensitive.
Can't say anything these days.
I couldn't get up here and be like,
"I believe in science,"
without pissing off half the country.
So my pitch to Netflix,
"I'm gonna get up here,
I'm gonna stand silently
for three minutes."
[laughter]
They said that won't work because
then what if people start jerking off…
[laughter]
…to a woman being quiet?
I was like, "But I have no tits,"
and they were like, "It doesn't matter."
[laughter]
They said "If people start jerking off
and come faster than three minutes,
we've created the same problem."
[laughter]
And I've literally
never won someone over in three minutes
'cause of how my face looks.
[laughter]
I should have stayed blonde.
I was blonde for one year, and that was
the most likable I've ever been.
Completely different lifestyle.
I did a TikTok dance
'cause when you're blonde,
you have to do those.
[laughter]
And I got a comment on the video
that said, "Blonde Mary Beth
is giving girl who would call me a slur
freshman year of high school."
[laughter]
"But would want me as her GBF
by senior year,
and I'm absolutely living for it."
[laughter]
And blondes definitely have more fun,
'cause nothing is expected of them.
Brunettes, we carry
the weight of the world on our shoulders.
[laughter]
We're expected to read.
We're expected to vote.
[laughter]
For one full year, no one thought
I was gonna do either of those things.
[laughter]
I felt so free.
And it definitely changed
people's perception of me.
'Cause if you see me brunette
with a blowout,
you're like, "That's a bisexual
standup comedian that lives in Brooklyn."
First immediate thought.
When I was blonde with a blowout,
I looked like
the proud mother of three sons.
[laughter]
Macklin, Declan and Brayden.
And one daughter
that I didn't really fuck with.
And I lived in Texas.
God, family, football.
[laughter]
I looked like an idiot.
And I don't care about being smart.
I don't care about being smart.
What's the point? Oppenheimer was smart.
[laughter]
Look what happened to him.
He still married a bitch!
[laughter]
I don't know if you guys saw Oppenheimer.
I saw it, I loved it. Won Best Picture.
I guess a lot of people thought that
Emily Blunt's character was unlikable.
In a movie
about the creator of the atomic bomb.
[laughter]
Just had to add a woman.
And I was blonde for a television show
that I'm in called Overcompensating.
[cheering]
And we film that in Toronto,
so I lived in Toronto
for four months last year.
I'm gonna move back
for four months this year.
Toronto's cute. It's sort of like
if they built New York City at Epcot.
[laughter]
Far away, it looks like a real city,
but if you knock on
any of the building facades, it's hollow.
[laughter]
And people say Canada is a lot safer
'cause there's no guns,
but I think
things also don't work as well.
So there's an airport in Toronto
called Billy Bishop, which…
That's not the name of an airport.
[laughter]
Billy Bishop?
That's Macklin, Declan and Brayden's dad.
[laughter]
That's my fake husband who I adore.
My siblings came to visit
while we were filming
and they were gonna
fly out of Billy Bishop,
so they got there, they went to check in,
and at the desk, they were like,
"So we're actually not flying today."
[laughter]
"We gave it some thought.
There's no flights, but good luck."
So now I think
maybe a few guns would be helpful.
[laughter]
Just keep people on their toes.
And of course, I want to write
more fun jokes about silly things,
but it's really dark up here.
I just think 9/11 happened when I was too
young for my brain to develop properly.
[laughter]
'Cause I was thinking about wordplay
and how we need to ban it.
I think it's gone too far. I was trying
to remember when I first had that thought.
It was when I was in London,
I was in a cab,
and we drove past a bar
that was called Jack the Chipper.
[laughter]
Which is a play on the name
of serial killer slash rapist
Jack the Ripper.
So that would be like if, in 20 years,
I opened a bar called Jeffrey Pepstein's.
[laughter]
With an adjoining bowling alley
called Ghis-lanes.
[laughter]
See how quickly I can go
from wordplay to sex trafficking.
[laughter]
British people are gonna hate that joke.
They're gonna be like,
"It's not chipper like happy."
"It's 'cause we call French fries chips."
And it's like, "Well, I'm the one
with the microphone, so…"
[laughter]
You have to always anticipate discourse.
That's what I've learned
from posting online.
Some of the jokes I'm gonna say tonight
I could never post online,
and I will point them out to you.
[laughter]
Feels safer to put them
on a global streaming platform
'cause there's no comments section.
And I've prepared a lot.
I'm taking this very seriously
'cause it's still very rare
for women to get Netflix specials.
[whooping]
[cheering and applause]
I had to have sex
with so many executives over there.
[laughter]
I was worried when they were gonna
maybe acquire Warner Brothers.
It's like, "I just had sex
with these Netflix guys
and now I have to bounce
on some brothers?"
[laughter]
"How many are there?"
Most of my peers are men.
Male comedians are
some of the worst people that we have.
[laughter]
Their personality disorder,
it's narcissists with depression.
Depressed, but also with narcissism.
It's like, "Do you hate yourself or not?"
[laughter]
Figure it out and let me know.
And all the comedians I loved growing up
are either disgraced or racist
or obsessed with trans people.
Or D, all of the above.
Ever since Katy Perry went to space,
I have no heroes left.
[laughter]
When a comedian is accused
of sexual misconduct,
I don't think
they should be forced into retirement.
They should tour more, if anything.
'Cause then we know their whereabouts.
[laughter]
What's worse than a sexual predator?
A sexual predator with nothing but time.
Like Chris D'Elia,
he was accused of being a pedophile,
so he took a year off,
and in that year, he had a baby.
[audience gasping]
So now he has
more access to kids than ever.
[gasping and laughter]
There's gonna be some tough concepts.
[laughter]
Some comedians don't have tough concepts.
I… I don't want kids, I decided.
-Yeah.
-[whooping]
I don't want kids
'cause it's too big of an age difference.
[laughter]
You're never gonna like
the same music and movies and stuff.
Hard to bridge that gap.
My friend from high school had a baby.
She's the first one from our little crew.
And now there's an eight-month-old boy
in our group chat.
[laughter]
And we're not even sure if he's gay.
Don't think I can be friends with someone
who doesn't have their shit figured out.
I don't want kids, but I'd love
to be six months pregnant for one day
so I could wear overalls.
[laughter]
Maybe paint an accent wall.
And plop down on a big, fluffy couch
and drink an ice-cold glass of lemonade.
There's no husband in the fantasy.
[laughter]
He passed away.
Afghanistan.
[laughter]
Not a soldier.
He was there for a bachelor party.
[laughter]
It was a fentanyl overdose.
I did have a really scary thought
the other day.
Imagine having a kid
if you didn't want one.
-[exhales slowly]
-[laughter]
Imagine having a kid if you didn't want…
Imagine having a lamp
if you didn't want one.
[laughter]
Like a lamp shows up at your house
you didn't order.
You're just like, "What the fuck
am I gonna do with this lamp?"
Then you have to keep it in your house
for 18 years.
I have my hands full right now.
I adopted a puppy.
[cheering]
Her name is Pinky.
She's a… Yeah.
[cheering]
She's a chihuahua from Tijuana.
She crossed the border to take the job
from an American chihuahua.
[laughter]
She just has better work ethic.
She is a dog and an immigrant.
We keep her away from Kristi Noem
for two reasons.
[laughter]
[applause]
Thank you.
I found a neurodivergent dog trainer
for Pinky.
[laughter]
I looked for one specifically 'cause
I didn't want it to be a hobby for them.
[laughter]
I wanted it to be an obsession.
So we're teaching her to bite.
[laughter]
No, I need her to be a good dog.
I had a bad dog once before
and I cannot go through that again.
Our family dog growing up,
her name was Bailey.
She was a Jack Russell terrier
and she held our family hostage.
[laughter]
She was a domestic terrorist.
I think it was the Irish in her.
[laughter]
I'm not just saying
she would bark at the vacuum.
Bailey would actually bite car tires
as people were pulling out of our driveway
and pop holes in them.
She was responsible for 17 flat tires
and three car bombs.
[laughter]
So I really need Pinky to be a good dog.
She's doing pretty well.
She's been pulling on a leash a bit
when we're out on walks.
So I called the trainer.
"What should I do?"
And she said,
"Well, some people put meat on a stick
and they take it on the walks with them
to keep the dog engaged."
[laughter]
I was like, "Okay, so what should I do?"
"I can't walk around Brooklyn
with meat on a stick."
[laughter]
"I'm in a TV show."
So I have to send her away
to a week-long intensive training camp.
I was filling out
the 90-minute onboarding survey
where you answer questions about your dog.
One of the questions was
"Has your dog ever bitten a human?"
"If so, please rate the severity
from one to seven."
So one was it left a mark,
but it didn't break the skin.
Seven was the victim died.
[laughter]
I was like,
"Are you guys training killer dogs here?"
But I caught myself being judgmental
because crime is a social issue.
[laughter]
And I'm raising Pinky
as an atheist socialist feminist.
[cheering and applause]
Sometimes I feel like I'm failing her.
'Cause your dog is a reflection of you,
and I'm really hard on myself.
We had a very tough moment.
We were at John F. Kennedy International
Airport. We were going on vacation.
It was six in the morning
and Pinky decided to take a shit
in the automated revolving door.
[laughter]
What do I mean by automated?
It just keeps going.
It was so early.
I was like, "She doesn't have to go yet."
As soon as we stepped inside
this revolving door, she took a shit.
It happened so fast.
There was nothing I could do.
When we walked out, I was panicking.
I'm like, "I need to tell someone."
"If I just leave this here, it will
eat away at me for the rest of my life."
And it's like, who do you tell
something like that to at the airport?
Everyone that works there now
just pushes wheelchairs.
[laughter]
Can't tell the ticketing desk.
They're so mean, they'll scream at me.
This isn't Canada, okay? They have guns.
[laughter]
So I thought the only appropriate thing
to do after what just happened,
I'm gonna get on the plane
and I'm gonna blow it up.
[laughter]
'Cause I'll never be allowed back at JFK.
So I went through security
thinking that's what I was gonna do.
[laughter]
And then I saw these two women
at the help desk at Terminal 4.
They had very kind faces.
I just walked up to them and I said,
"Um, something really bad just happened."
[laughter]
They said, "What?"
I said, "My dog took a shit
in the revolving door."
Keep in mind, every second
I'm waiting to tell someone about this,
the shit's just going
around and around and around.
[laughter]
So I told them my dog took a shit
in the automated revolving door.
But when she put her hand on my hand,
she said, "It's going to be okay."
[laughter]
We had a laugh about it.
She said, "We'll call upstairs,
they'll stop the door, they'll clean it,
and also, this has never happened before."
[laughter]
And then I was feeling a little proud.
And I looked down at Pinky and I said,
"Well-behaved women rarely make history."
[laughter and applause]
Pinky is very inspiring to me.
She's actually inspired me
to write a movie.
It's a body swap comedy.
[laughter]
And it's about a girl
whose dog swaps bodies with her boyfriend.
And not that much changes.
[laughter]
And in fact,
their relationship gets better.
[laughter]
The dog finally teaches the woman
what unconditional love is.
Then the boyfriend
kind of likes being a dog
'cause then he gets to contribute
to the household even less.
So they decide not to swap back.
[laughter]
And the movie's called Stay.
But I'm gonna set it in 2019.
Everything I write from now on
I'm just gonna set in 2019,
so I don't have to address Ozempic.
[laughter]
Ozempic really brings out the worst in me.
Of course I'm happy it's available
for people who need it as medicine.
My dad was a doctor. I love medicine.
I support pharma, big and small.
But as someone
that had an eating disorder,
I don't think it's fair that rich people
get the benefits of a mental illness
without actually having it.
[laughter]
No one wants to get off their ass
and have an eating disorder anymore.
[laughter]
So imagine if I posted that joke online.
Someone discovered me through that joke.
[laughter]
And I definitely wouldn't recommend
getting an eating disorder.
It's not worth it.
Like, you save a lot of money.
[laughter]
But you have all the problems
you had before,
then on top of that, you're hungry.
I know that's resonating
with, like, four girls in here.
-[laughter]
-[woman] Whoo!
And hey, maybe one guy.
[laughter]
It's 2026. Guys can have 'em now.
I think it's called intermittent fasting.
[laughter and applause]
I'm a comedian, but I give back.
I'm also an actor.
And with acting, it's a lot
of auditioning. It's a lot of rejection.
That can affect your self-esteem.
Sometimes you get an audition
and you're like,
"I hope I'm not right for that."
They send you a description.
I got an audition once.
The character's name was Sally.
The description said, "Sexy but thin
trailer park, meth addict type…"
[laughter]
"…who's seen better days."
Which means that casting saw my headshot,
and they were like,
"This could be our girl."
[laughter]
Trailer park, meth addict type
who's seen better days.
It was actually pretty tame
for a Ryan Murphy project.
[laughter]
I was relieved I did not book that one.
The show that I'm in, Overcompensating,
is about college students,
which is much more my speed at 34.
We filmed a few days on a college campus,
which brought back a lot of memories.
So, who here went to college?
Clap if you went to college.
[applause]
If you went in the US or Canada,
you might remember, on campus, they had
these emergency phones every 200 feet.
These giant red poles with a blue light
on top of them, and they were phones.
When I got to college,
it was explained that those were installed
to help combat sexual assault on campus.
So to me, that just shows
a fundamental misunderstanding
of how sexual assault works.
[laughter]
They don't let you make a phone call.
Did you guys think
they were letting us make a phone call?
[laughter]
I would have loved
to be in that brainstorm.
Trying to come up with ways
to combat sexual assault on campus,
there's one woman in the room
and she's like,
"We could just expel students
who assault other students."
Then one of the guys, he's a lot louder,
and he's like, "Those are my friends."
[laughter]
Then another guy's like,
"What if we had more phones?"
"Maybe it's just, like, a lack of phones."
[laughter]
Both of those men are in Congress now.
Democrats.
[laughter]
[applause]
I don't hate straight guys.
I don't, despite their best efforts.
[laughter]
I'm actually dating one right now.
I'm in a relationship. Yeah.
[cheering]
I'm in an open relationship.
My boyfriend and I are very open.
We broke up.
[laughter]
That's about as open as it gets.
And we did long distance
New York to London for five years
'cause he's British.
So the day we broke up,
I walked out of my apartment,
I went over to the East River
and I just dumped a teabag in there.
[laughter]
It felt like the right thing to do.
And being single when you're bisexual,
it's like, "Really? No one?"
[laughter]
'Cause it's out of everyone.
And it's still no one.
[laughter]
But it feels different this time
'cause I have zero interest
in having casual sex with strangers.
I'm just not casual sex girl,
and it took me 34 years on this Earth
to admit that about myself.
I fall in love with almost every
single person I've ever had sex with.
I put my entire self-worth
and my life's happiness in their hands.
When they don't respond to a text from me,
I go into a state of deep psychosis.
[laughter]
Because women really
come into their own as storytellers
when we're waiting on a text back.
[laughter and scattered applause]
Sabrina Carpenter's written,
like, three albums about it.
[laughter]
Casual sex is like religion.
It'd be so cool if it was real.
[laughter]
[applause]
And I pretended to believe for a while,
just in case.
[laughter]
I don't even know
what the sex trends are now.
Last time I was single, it was choking.
Where do we go from there? Drowning?
[laughter]
Having someone hit me with their car?
Then I think about myself in my twenties,
getting choked by a stranger,
drunk and probably on a weeknight.
[laughter]
Being a woman in your twenties
is a horror movie.
If there are any women here
in their twenties, it gets better.
Well, it doesn't get better.
[laughter]
But you're more tired,
so you make better choices.
[laughter]
And I still dabble, of course.
I'll backslide sometimes.
I was hooking up with this guy
and I was giving him a hand job
'cause I like to reference the classics.
[laughter]
I was just doing my thing.
I was going for it.
And he just came.
[laughter]
He didn't tell me.
But I kind of liked it.
[laughter]
It felt very
"our next guest needs no introduction."
[laughter]
Turn of the century almost.
Like before they knew
to smile in pictures.
That got me thinking, when did that start?
When did men start announcing
that they were gonna come?
Couldn't have been that long ago.
[laughter]
No way men were going overseas
and killing Nazis
and then coming back and doing that.
[laughter]
Like, "Martha, Martha."
"I'm gonna come."
[laughter]
It doesn't sound right.
When I hook up with guys, I'm doing bits.
[laughter]
Because I have to make it fun for me.
Sex is for them. The bits are for me.
[laughter]
So I have this bit that I do
after I have sex with a guy.
I'll straddle him,
and I'll look down and I'll say,
"I could put this pillow over your face
right now and kill you."
[laughter]
And then I laugh.
I had sex with this guy
who had a bunch of tattoos.
I just had a feeling I wasn't gonna hear
from him again, 'cause of the tattoos.
[laughter]
He wouldn't tell me
what any of his tattoos meant. He refused.
So after we had sex,
I turned to him and I said,
"I should probably know what your tattoos
mean if I'm having your baby."
[laughter]
I didn't hear from him.
So I took matters into my own hands.
I got an STD test
so I had an excuse to reach out.
[laughter]
I did that. I was patient.
I got the test, got the results.
I texted him, I said, "I got an STD test.
Results were negative."
"Still pregnant though."
[laughter]
And I did that for me.
I'm reading a book called
Radical Acceptance: Embracing Life
with the Heart of a Buddha.
So I'm doing good.
[laughter]
It's a universal sign
for someone that's doing good.
I don't think it's fair that
I have to reach spiritual enlightenment
to function in a relationship.
It's like, what's my future partner
doing right now?
Probably watching a YouTube compilation
of someone else playing video games.
[laughter]
Why?
Why is that entertaining?
Have you ever hooked up with someone
so immature it actually feels predatory?
[laughter]
All the women in here.
The founder of Bumble said
that she thinks the future of dating
is you create an AI, and that goes
on a date with someone else's AI,
and you see if they're compatible.
So now I think
there should be less women in STEM.
[laughter]
I think we may have overcorrected.
I do date women as well.
[whooping]
But if I end up with a woman, that's
two crazy people living in the house.
[laughter]
'Cause women are crazy.
I think we need to embrace it more.
We need to let it empower us.
When men are crazy,
they don't let it hold them back.
they, like, redraw congressional maps.
[laughter]
We could be harnessing the crazy a bit
more. I'll talk about that at the end.
And crazy is a spectrum, of course.
You know how there's lowercase T trauma
and capital T trauma?
I think there's lowercase C crazy
and capital C crazy.
So I know this girl
who ran into her crush on the sidewalk,
so she lied
and pretended to have a podcast
so that she could sit down
and interview him for two hours…
[laughter]
…recorded it,
and she considered that their first date.
[laughter]
So that's obviously lowercase C crazy.
And then capital C crazy,
I guess the classic example
is, like, faking a pregnancy.
But then I'm like, "I kind of wanna hear
her side of the story."
Maybe it's a hilarious bit she was doing.
[laughter]
To a guy with tattoos.
But men are not allowed to call us crazy.
That's a slur,
'cause they don't use it right.
Guys will be like, "Yeah,
my girl's crazy. She'll, like, call me."
[laughter]
"She wants me to pick up."
And girls are like, "Yeah, my guy's crazy.
He tried to kill my mom."
[laughter]
"But we got through it.
She was being kind of mouthy that day."
[laughter]
I know a lot of bisexual girls
come to my shows.
I want to start hosting
bi girl mixers before
where you can all meet
and become friends, but never hook up.
[laughter]
Bi girls don't really
want to date each other.
Bi girls only want to date straight guys
who look gay,
and the scariest lesbians
you've ever seen.
[laughter]
You haven't lived until you've been
ghosted by a power lesbian in a fedora.
[laughter]
Because that happened to me.
She was so old.
[laughter]
She was so old
that when she put her number in my phone…
I don't know why she bothered,
'cause she never texted me back.
She actually filled in the birthday field.
[laughter]
So now her birthday
is permanently on my iCalendar.
[laughter]
I can't remove it.
Lisa, 48 this year.
[laughter]
Congrats. That's a big one.
Who here likes doggie?
Clap if you like doggie style.
[cheering and applause]
For those of you that didn't clap, what do
you do when you want sex to be over?
[laughter]
You can DM me. I'm genuinely curious.
My advice to queer businesses.
[laughter]
People are always asking me,
"Mary Beth, you're a comedian."
"What's your advice to queer businesses?"
[laughter]
And queer businesses are those
little storefronts with a pride flag,
and they sell, like, soaps,
and key chains, and artisanal condiments.
My advice to queer businesses,
you have to be open sometimes.
[laughter]
I would love to engage
in a transaction with you,
but I'm not able to.
I went to patronize
a queer business in Brooklyn once.
I got there. It was closed, obviously,
'cause it was a Wednesday.
[laughter]
And the hours on the door said
"Thursday to Monday, 1 p.m. to 6 p.m."
[laughter]
My head was spinning.
I was like, "Monday comes first."
[laughter]
I'd never seen it written out like that.
And I never did get to shop there,
but now I manage my expectations.
Like, I ordered a T-shirt online
from this trans designer who I love,
and I got an email about a week later
saying my T-shirt was gonna be delayed.
I was like, "Oh, I never thought
I was getting a T-shirt."
[laughter]
I just wanted to support.
I do think I should be in charge of more
things, 'cause I have really good ideas.
There was a period last year
where I was actually considering
running for mayor of New York.
I'm so glad I didn't have to
because I really didn't feel like it.
[laughter]
But I thought through
what I would do if I was mayor.
First thing I'd do
if I'm mayor of New York City,
I'm gonna close Rikers,
which is this really fucked-up prison.
[cheering and applause]
Second thing I'm gonna do,
I'm gonna reopen
the Triangle Shirtwaist factory.
[laughter]
As a gay club.
[cheering]
You're on board. Okay.
If you missed that day in history,
the Triangle Shirtwaist factory
was a garment factory in Lower Manhattan
where women and children worked.
We would have all been best friends
working there.
[laughter]
But they used to lock the workers in
so they couldn't steal.
One day in 1911, there was this huge fire
and everyone that worked there died.
So it's that space, but it's a gay club.
[laughter]
Just picture it.
You're at the Triangle Shirtwaist factory.
It's, like, a warehouse. You're dancing.
You're on ketamine.
Once per night, we do a smoke machine
to honor those we lost.
[laughter]
Next thing I'd do if I was mayor,
I wanna host, in New York City,
the Oppression Olympics.
[laughter]
I'm sick of all the discourse.
I wanna know who really has it the worst.
[laughter]
And I don't think white gay guys
are gonna be very happy.
[laughter]
[inaudible]
I love you guys.
I can always tell
when a gay guy is pure of heart.
If he's not obsessed with me,
then he's not.
[laughter]
But I'm not a gay guy
trapped in a woman's body.
I'm a woman trapped in a woman's body.
[laughter]
If there was a gay guy in here,
I think I'd be a lot happier.
[laughter]
My first boyfriend was gay,
and we remained close.
I actually officiated his wedding.
And he and his husband recently welcomed
a new addition to their family.
It's a boy named Luke.
He's a 31-year-old photo editor.
[laughter]
And they're happily in a throuple.
I don't like to generalize queer people,
but I think we can all agree
that gay guys are horny.
[laughter]
If gay men could conceive babies
through butt stuff,
the population wouldn't be declining.
[laughter]
And they are doing the fucking work.
Do you know how much prep
goes into gay sex?
And I don't just mean the pill they take
that's literally called PrEP.
They have to douche.
They have to put a towel down.
They have to find a remote location
in the forest 'cause their husband's home.
[laughter]
He's cool with it.
He just has a Zoom call at that time.
Even lesbians,
they have to carry backpacks.
[laughter]
See a girl at the club with a backpack,
that's a lesbian and those are her tools.
[laughter]
We'll have free backpack check
at the Triangle Shirtwaist factory.
[laughter]
In solidarity.
I just think straight sex
could benefit from a few more steps.
A few more moments of pause to decide
if it's something you really wanna do.
The stakes with straight sex
are so much higher
and we don't acknowledge that.
If straight sex goes wrong,
you could accidentally create human life.
Remember that lamp? Eighteen years.
If gay sex goes wrong, worst case,
you have to change the fitted sheet.
[laughter]
And if you laughed at that,
then I know you've done anal.
[laughter]
I think communication in sex is important,
and you have your go-tos, right?
You have "Oh my God"
and you have "Oh fuck."
[laughter]
I think if you're an "Oh my God,"
you kind of have to find an "Oh fuck."
You can't have two "Oh my Gods."
Two people saying "Oh my God"
back and forth.
[laughter]
"Oh my God, oh my God, oh my God."
That's not sex. That's an emergency.
[laughter]
That's your toast just caught fire.
And then two "Oh fucks."
"Oh fuck, oh fuck, oh fuck."
That's not sex.
That's talking shit about someone
and you check to see
if you're sending them a voice note.
[laughter]
And you are sending them a voice note.
My goal with that joke
is that next time any of you
are having sex and one of you says it,
you start laughing.
[laughter]
You have to tell the person
that you're having sex with,
"Sorry, I was just thinking
about Mary Beth."
[laughter]
[cheering and applause]
Are you an "Oh my God" or an "Oh fuck?"
"Oh fuck." And are you single?
-[woman] Yes.
-Oh my God!
[laughter]
Your "Oh my God" could be in here.
It does feel very binary.
It's sort of like the top and bottom thing
for gay guys.
By the way, I love that gay men
have decided the one way to offend them
is to ask if they're a top or bottom.
It's like, "Sorry, you just asked to see
a picture of my boyfriend's hard dick."
[laughter]
"But now we're Christian. Okay."
"You told a story
about getting your butthole fingered
in the hot tub at Le Bain."
[laughter]
"But I crossed a line and I'm sorry."
My sister-in-law was telling me a story
about the bartender
at her favorite bar in Austin.
He got fired for drinking on the job.
He was taking 12 shots
throughout his shift.
I was like, "Was he gay?"
She was like, "Why does that matter?"
I was like, "It actually
couldn't matter more to the story."
[laughter]
That's the difference
between a comedy and a drama.
[laughter]
If a straight man
is taking 12 shots at work,
that's the saddest story I've ever heard.
[laughter]
That's Manchester By The Sea.
You should get him the help he needs.
If a gay guy's taking 12 shots at work,
I'm like, "Invite him to Thanksgiving."
[laughter]
He sounds fun.
My first gay guy ever
was my mom's brother,
my gay uncle Greg.
We just call him Uncle Greg.
[laughter]
And he's so iconic.
He came out in the '70s.
He was at the very first Pride March ever.
And he starts every text to me
with, "Hey, diva."
[laughter]
He speaks seven languages. Very eccentric.
He would be played
by Philip Seymour Hoffman in a movie.
Just to give you an idea of this person.
And I don't know if anyone here has elders
who scroll on their iPhone like this,
but this is how my Uncle Greg scrolls.
Whoosh!
[laughter]
Like he's about to blast off.
He's an excellent dinner guest
'cause you truly never know
what's gonna come out of his mouth.
We were at Christmas dinner
this past year.
Twenty of us sat around the table
at my parents' house.
And my Uncle Greg looks at me and he goes,
"Have you ever considered
doing yourself up as Michael Jackson?"
[laughter]
And then he said, "It wouldn't take much."
But it wasn't shade.
That question came into his head,
so he said it out loud.
And you kind of see it, right?
I was between spray tans.
I didn't know how to begin to answer that,
so I was just like, "No." [chuckles]
[laughter]
"Never thought of that."
And I asked my Uncle Greg once…
I was like, "How did you
get out of going to Vietnam?"
It's a fun question to ask old guys,
to bond with them.
He said he had to go down
to City Hall in New York
and write on a piece of paper three times,
"I am a practicing homosexual."
And then he didn't have to go.
So now I think British actors should have
to do that before they take gay roles.
Josh O'Connor, two more times.
[laughter]
Andrew Garfield, let's see it.
Daniel Day-Lewis, I didn't forget
you played Lincoln.
[laughter and applause]
That's another joke
I couldn't really post online.
Comments would be like,
"So you're policing people's sexuality?"
Well, someone should.
[laughter]
I guess that has to be me.
Posting online isn't all bad.
Sometimes I post things online
and actually learn.
So I have this theory
that there's two types of white dads.
You either have a white dad
that cares how you load the dishwasher,
or you have a white dad
that cheats on your mom.
[laughter]
Posted that online,
comment section went crazy.
Turns out a lot
of white dads are cheating.
[laughter]
I got a bunch of comments that said,
"Well, there's a third type
of white dad. Autistic."
[laughter]
To me, that falls under dishwasher dad.
If a man has little projects,
he's not stepping out on his woman.
[laughter]
Then I got just a few comments that said,
"My dad is a cheater,
but my stepdad is a dishwasher dad."
Isn't that sweet?
[laughter]
Second chances at love are real.
My dad was solidly a dishwasher dad.
My parents had six kids,
and they were married for 51 years.
[cheering and applause]
Great for them.
A bit of a missed opportunity for me.
Because I would have done amazing work
as someone's bitchy teenage stepdaughter.
Watch this.
Rick!
[laughter]
[tearfully] You are not my dad.
Now give me a hundred dollars.
Thank you.
[laughter and applause]
The audition that never came through.
My dad died last year,
which I'm still heartbroken over
'cause I loved him so much.
I was so proud that he was my dad.
He was a surgeon, son of an immigrant.
From Italy. Not like a real one.
[laughter]
And I'm being told that because we had
a great relationship and he died,
I now get to be a psycho
for one full year.
A reward. When you have
a bad relationship with your dad,
you get to be a psycho your whole life.
So I just get the one year,
but I keep deferring
'cause I don't know what I wanna do.
[laughter]
Drug habit's too easy.
My slut years are behind me,
and I didn't even need an excuse for that.
I'm looking for inspiration.
I saw an ad. There was a woman,
she had a tattoo right here.
For one split second, I was like,
"Maybe it's a pussy tattoo."
[laughter]
Or I've been really compelled
to comment on my ex's Instagram,
"You have no integrity."
[laughter and applause]
Can you imagine if you saw that?
An actor posts a carousel
from a photo shoot,
I'm in the comments,
"You have no integrity."
[laughter]
No punctuation, no capitalization.
It's not the British ex either.
[sighs] I can't tell you who it is,
but I really want to.
When you see the comment, you'll know.
And then my year
of being a psycho has begun.
[laughter]
So many bad men are still alive,
but my dad had to die?
Woody Allen is 90.
[laughter]
JK Rowling.
[laughter and applause]
I hate his books.
[laughter]
[whooping]
So long.
Joe Biden.
That bag of bones outlived my dad.
[laughter]
And do you know how many genocides
my dad helped fund?
Zero.
[laughter]
Some of my friends
still have grandparents.
I'm like, "Don't come to me
with that shit."
If your grandparent dies
when you're in your thirties,
you should be at work the next day.
[laughter]
You had enough time.
I do think the most important relationship
in a young woman's life
is the one with her dad,
but there's another very telling,
very formative relationship
that we don't talk about as a culture,
and that is a young woman's relationship
with her ex-best friend.
[laughter]
[laughter builds]
Did you hear that?
She's in your mind.
[laughter]
I wanted to tell the story
of my falling out with my ex-best friend,
but because I did everything right
and nothing wrong,
it just sounds like I'm being mean.
So instead, I've been asking
if anyone here at the show
wants to share the story of their
falling out with their ex-best friend,
and I will tell you definitively
if you were right or wrong.
So I heard hundreds of these stories,
and these wounds run very deep.
One girl got the mic,
she told a 20-minute story
that involved Hurricane Sandy…
[laughter]
…and Hobby Lobby.
And then she told me
her ex-best friend's name was Anastasia.
[laughter]
I was like,
"I don't want to victim blame, but
if you meet a girl named Anastasia…"
[laughter]
"…and make her your best friend,
you kind of have it coming."
[laughter]
One girl in Pittsburgh, she was catfished
by her best friend for a full year.
[audience gasping]
The best friend pretended
to be a boy from another school.
The way she figured it out,
she went in her best friend's Google
search history, and the first thing was,
"How to tell my best friend
I've been catfishing her."
[laughter]
The second thing was,
"How do I know if I'm a lesbian?"
[laughter]
And the third one was,
"Fedoras in my area."
[laughter and applause]
We are gonna ask if anyone here
wants to share their story, just to see.
So does anyone in the… Oh, I saw a hand.
Actually, let's do this one right here.
Look at this hot guy
that's bringing a microphone.
-What's your name?
-My name's Grace.
-[Mary Beth] What happened?
-So it all went down in 2019.
We were best friends for 20 years.
And you know
when you're, like, BFFs for 20 years,
and then it's like kind of gay
at that point a little bit?
[laughter]
There's a moment in every 20-year
female-to-female friendship
where you say, "Are we fucking or not?"
-[Grace] Yeah.
-[laughter]
Let's just say she knew me.
She knew me well.
And, um, my mom passed away in 2018,
and I, like, fell into a depression
for, like, a year.
When moms die, you have to be depressed.
Dads, it's psycho. It's a bit more fun.
Yeah. Yeah, so I was,
like, super depressed.
Wasn't really responding to texts.
I mean, like, even more so than usual.
Like, I'm a bad texter.
-Um…
-Ooh.
[Grace laughs]
Doesn't bode well
for if you're right or wrong, but…
But we were going to Coachella Weekend 1.
I was, like, people-pleasing.
Like, trying to be a good friend.
My mom died. I was still sad.
So right after we decided,
we got tickets to Coachella Weekend 1…
And then my boyfriend
surprises me with a card.
And he was there with me
when my mom passed away.
Like, literally there.
Like, watched her pass away. Yeah.
Yes.
-Yes, give it up for him.
-[applause]
-Yes.
-What a king.
-Mensch.
-Are you still with him?
-[Grace] I am.
-Okay.
My boyfriend, um, surprises me with a card
and he's like,
"I'm going to run the Boston Marathon
and raise $10,000 for ALS."
It was the same weekend as Coachella.
Like it's Marathon Monday in Boston,
and Coachella was, like, the same weekend.
Can I just say surprising someone
with a card
that says "I'm running a marathon…"
[laughter]
…is… It's one of the worst surprises
I could possibly think of.
[laughter]
I love a grand gesture.
I don't know. I'm straight, so like…
Except for the friend thing.
So you told your best friend,
"I'm sorry to say, unfortunately,
I cannot go to Coachella Weekend 1."
Weekend 1. But I will go Weekend 2.
We can just simply sell the tickets
and go Weekend 2.
She's like, "I wanna go Weekend 1
because that's when
all the celebrities go and stuff."
-So she was like--
-So she has a bad heart.
[Grace] Yeah.
She has a dark energy.
[Grace] Very dark energy.
So basically, like, we had a falling out
after that, and she sent me…
Ironically, 'cause you know
I hate texting.
She sent me, like, a 30-page text breakup.
After that, you didn't speak at all?
Literally didn't speak. I was crying.
And I will say she was
a loyal, loyal friend for 20 years.
Okay. You offered a compromise,
which was to go to Coachella Weekend 2,
which is more than fair.
And maybe she was
harboring some resentments,
but also your mom died.
So I think in this situation,
I do believe that you were in the right.
[Grace] Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
'Cause you have
to honor your relationship.
But it sounds to me like there could be
a reconciliation in your future.
That's what it feels like.
Maybe not over text, right?
Definitely not.
[Mary Beth] Maybe you could send an email
or a gesture like that.
Just be careful with reconciling.
I tried to reconcile
with my ex-best friend.
We hadn't spoken in eight years,
then we FaceTimed on January 1st, 2020.
A lot of people think that's actually
what caused the COVID-19 pandemic.
[laughter]
So just tread lightly.
Because I think there's still
some love on the table on this one.
Do you feel that? What's her first name?
Her name's Tatiana, Tanya.
-[exhales]
-[Grace giggles]
Should have led with that.
[laughter]
She's from Belarus.
No, totally.
[laughter]
Thank you, Grace, for sharing.
That's beautiful.
[cheering]
Wow.
Are there any porn addicts here?
[laughter]
-[audience member] Whoo!
-There's no straight guys here?
[laughter]
Straight guys love porn.
I was stuck in a conversation
with a straight guy,
so I just asked him, like,
"What type of porn do you watch?"
That's kind of the "How did you get out
of going to Vietnam?" of our generation.
[laughter]
There's always a story there.
And he told me he likes to go on Pornhub
and type in "hot girls."
[laughter]
Which I thought was pretty wholesome.
He turned the question back to me.
He asked what type of porn I watch.
I watch squirting porn.
I love squirting porn.
It's genre-bending.
It's action. It's comedy.
[laughter]
It's got a little something for everyone.
Then he asked a follow-up question. I was
pretty impressed. That's two questions.
He said, "Do you think squirt is pee?"
And I was like, "How do I not know?"
[laughter]
Could we get one scientist
to look into it for one day?
When I was touring,
I did this joke at a show,
and this girl was like,
"It's pee. I know it's pee."
[laughter]
I was like, "How?"
She was like, "I read this study."
[laughter]
So I looked it up. It turns out
Japanese scientists found five squirters.
[laughter]
I didn't know
five people could be a study.
It turns out I've also done a study.
[laughter]
Japanese scientists found
these five squirters.
[laughter]
M… made them squirt.
Filmed it for some reason.
[laughter]
Then they tested the squirt.
And what they found was that it is pee,
but it's not just pee.
[laughter]
And the other stuff,
they don't know what it is…
[laughter]
…or where it comes from.
So that was when I learned that
squirting porn is also science fiction.
[laughter]
It's pretty cool.
I was hooking up with this guy
who was really self-righteous
about the fact he didn't watch porn.
I was like, "What do you do
when you're jerking off?"
He said, "I go on Reddit and look
at pictures of naked people having sex."
[laughter]
I didn't have the heart to tell him.
Walking around with this galaxy brain,
I am plagued by many
deep and philosophical questions.
You've all heard,
if you had a time machine,
would you go back and kill baby Hitler?
I think so much has happened since then.
We need a modern adaptation
of the question.
So now I think it's,
if you had a time machine,
would you go back
and have sex with Mark Zuckerberg
to prevent him
from inventing the Facebook?
[laughter]
So, would you?
Would you have sex with Mark Zuckerberg?
[woman] Yeah, no.
-No.
-No. Typical white liberal.
[laughter]
I would volunteer myself, but I think
if I had sex with Mark Zuckerberg,
he would invent something worse.
[laughter]
I don't want to find out
what that would be.
There's a lot of pressure on comedians
to use our platform responsibly.
I get DMs all the time. "Why aren't
you posting more about the environment,
about the genocide?"
"Why aren't you
posting more about Wicked?"
[laughter]
It's like, "Sorry,
I'm reading a study on squirting."
[laughter]
Then I'll post.
I think we're moving forward.
Sometimes it doesn't feel like that,
but it's the little things you notice.
I was a child of the '90s.
When I was a kid,
society had sort of decided
that the most embarrassing job a person
could have was to work at McDonald's,
which is not even embarrassing.
Back then it was like, "What are you
gonna do? Go work at McDonald's?"
"Flip burgers? They'll hire anyone."
And I think we're moving forward,
because I truly believe, in 2026,
the most embarrassing job
a person could have
is being a police officer.
[laughter and applause]
[whooping]
If someone tells me they're a cop,
I'm like… [laughs]
[laughter]
"What?"
"You know strippers
dress up as you, right?"
[laughter]
And the cops will hire anyone.
I have to give credit where credit is due.
Cops are good at two things.
First, killing people, obviously.
And the second is merch.
Wow.
[laughter]
The NYPD has some fabulous merch.
You can actually buy NYPD merch
at any New York airport.
Like it's a sports team.
There are teens in France
walking around with NYPD T-shirts.
So if we want to abolish the police,
we need that type of footprint.
So I'm planning to open
a queer, abolitionist T-shirt shop.
[laughter]
We're open Tuesdays and Thursdays,
from 1 a.m. to 6 a.m.
[laughter]
And I hope we can count on your business.
[cheering and applause]
I don't do impressions,
and I don't do physical comedy,
but tonight I will be doing my impression
of a pussy in a denim romper.
[cheering]
This is a pussy in a denim romper.
[laughter]
Let me out!
I can't breathe!
[cheering and applause]
Democrats don't have a plan.
[laughter]
I've talked about it before.
I used to be a Republican.
And I will say I miss winning.
[laughter]
Republicans always have a plan.
Did you see Project 2025?
That shit was airtight.
That shit was like
a pussy in a denim romper.
[laughter]
And it just sucks that Republicans only
care about making billionaires richer,
and protecting pedophiles,
and taking away people's healthcare.
If they actually wanted to make
America great, we would live in a utopia.
They're so good at manipulating laws.
And then Democrats are like,
"We don't know any laws."
[laughter]
"Are they written down anywhere?"
Democrats are trying to fight fascism
with the Jiffy keyboard.
[laughter]
And I know we need better candidates.
And we all really need to vote.
That should go without saying.
[whooping and applause]
But some of you didn't.
Some of you didn't vote. I'm looking
at all the blonde people in here.
[laughter]
We need to expect more.
And I am also starting a grassroots
movement to win the next election.
So this is something that every single
woman in this room can participate in.
And, hey, gay guys too.
Come on, let's be helpful for once.
[laughter]
So I know when you see a guy
on a dating app
whose political views
are listed as moderate,
you usually just keep swiping.
Because moderate, of course,
just means Republican.
But we really need the votes.
So I'm gonna need you
to start matching with these guys.
I need you to go on dates with them.
And I'm gonna need you
to have sex with them.
[laughter]
And then I need you
to start sending them articles
from a left-leaning publication,
if you can find one.
[laughter]
And it's not gonna be fun.
I know they're gonna be
wearing really ugly pants.
[laughter]
You're gonna have to listen to them
talk about, like, free markets
or whatever the hell they believe in.
But we have to radicalize these moderates.
And I did the math.
If every single woman
has sex with about 1,000 moderates…
[laughter]
…we might be able to win this thing.
[laughter and applause]
[cheering]
So, my fellow Americans,
I want you to ask not
what your country can do for you,
but what your cunt
can do for your country.
[cheering]
That's so nice. [chuckles]
Thank you all so much. That's the show.
[cheering continues]
I love you all! Thank you.
["Galaxy Brain"
by The Japanese House plays]
♪ Wishing that someone ♪
♪ Would film the way I'm looking at you ♪
♪ I've been thinking about ♪
♪ Wishing that someone
Would film the way I'm looking at you ♪
♪ I've been thinking about ♪
♪ Wishing that someone
Would film the way I'm looking at you ♪
♪ I've been thinking about ♪
♪ Wishing that someone
Would film the way I'm looking at you ♪
♪ My storyline ♪
♪ And how your past becomes your present ♪
♪ If it's always on your mind ♪
♪ My storyline ♪
♪ I've been thinking about ♪
[music fades]